Hello everyone. Uh, my name is Phat.
I'm a master student, uh,
of computer science
in Concordia University in Chicago.
So today,
I will mention about the software
engineering,
with-- will,
will covering the introduction,
key concept,
software cost and maintenance,
and the challenges.
All right, let's start it.
Okay, let's go detail on the topics.
So we will have five-- four sections.
One is the introduction to software
engineering, uh, key
concept in software engineering,
software cost and
man-maintenance, challenge
in software engineering.
So now we're gonna go through the
definition of the software engineering.
So what is the engineering? So the
engineering,
uh,
is the application of scientific principle
and method to the construction of useful
structure
and machine. So for example,
we have many kind of engineerings.
Engineer is mechanical engineer,
civil engineer,
electrical engineering.
So each kind of engineering cover
different.
So for example,
mechanical engineering most
cover up the, uh, industry machine.
Uh, electrical engineering,
they do like handling,
uh, electric and, uh, electric system.
So for the software, we-- the engineering
will cover up the
software, the application
that been used in many kind of device,
including,
uh, clients
and s-host. So in a client, we will
have like, uh, different kinds,
uh, that for end user,
where you can see as mobile app.
Or the server hosting
is more like operating
system hosting, uh, application.
So the term,
we will know about like some history where
the term come from.
So it is the term happening
appear like fifty-four years ago.
It's in NATO conferences at the
Garmisch,
Germany in October
seven to eleven, nineteen six-sixty-eight,
in Rome, Italy,
October twenty-seven, thirty-one,
nineteen sixty-nine.
The reality is,
is the finally begin to arrive and
computer science has the sci-scientific
basics.
So for the software engineering
and professional development, the
development of the software system
cover up the whole size of complexity
warrant,
uh, teams of engineers and
multi-person construction.
The economies of
the,
of all developed
nation are dependent on software
concerned with the theories, method,
and tools for
professional software development.
Expenditure
represent a significant fraction of
GNP in all developed countries.
So, uh, for the professional development,
they will spread out many kinds of roles:
architect,
developer, manager, tester,
and cus-customer and
user.
Each role handling a different kind of the
usage or develop the,
um,
develop the software.
So
there's two kinds, uh, in software.
One is software engineer
and software programming.
So for the software programming
is more like the
small scale, one main job. They do
single developer and like
we can call it toy application, like
small scale, small scale, uh,
um, not heavily used,
not many people know about it.
For personally source li-lifespan,
it's been used
for like a few months or few weeks,
depends on
request or requirement of the software.
Uh, f-so for that case,
a single software,
single application will...
Or project will handily handle by one
person.
They will do all of the stuff is
architect, developing it,
manage the project,
testing the, the software,
and be the customer and the user.
And it's also fit in one kind of system
and
build from scratch. It's like you start
from the idea to the end.
And minimal maintenance because
it's not, uh,
it's not used for many people. It's not
need to developing.
It's not need to change based on the
system.
They not need to add more features.
So there's requirement on maintenance
is minimal.
For the software engineering,
it's like a whole team with
different kinds of roles.
Um,
they will deal with the complex system
and, and then
the,
and then finite,
uh,
lifespan. So
one product can be used till there's no
more
user. And every single
Teammate will handling different,
um,
role and they will handling different kind
of, uh,
uh,
response
in the whole system, in the,
in the whole system and the project's, uh,
development lifespan.
And for this kind,
they will fit in the system
fa- families.
So this mean you can, uh, for example,
we have
many kind of operating system like
Windows,
uh, Linux,
uh, Window, macOS,
um, Android, Linux, and for Android,
there are different kind
of application for it. And Linux is
many more different kind of operating
system based on that.
But if you're building a software
or the application
that will fit in all kinds of
operating system,
or you can understand it based on the
development of technology,
will-- you will able to use it
and manage it,
and you have to change based on the
architecture change.
And also the reuse to amortize cost
and the manage account for over sixty
percent of
overall development cost.
Software engineering
is a unique brand of engineering
because it's malleable.
Con- construction is hum- human
intensive,
intangible. S- software problem are
unprecedentedly complex,
and it's directly depend up- upon the
hardware,
the top of system engineering food chain.
And the software solution
is require unusual gear
and has discontinuous
operational nature.
For each of this,
we will-- I can ex-
explain a little bit more,
um, it's why it's, uh,
differently than the
other. So the software engineering,
they have to deal with the,
um,
they have to developing
and manage the software based on the
requirement or the current hardware been
applying
for end user, apply
or been used by end user
or the system.
So you can understand there's many
kind of situation happening
when your application
using,
uh,
application not fit in different kinds of,
uh, system configuration. For example,
uh,
like I says,
the operating system different
is my cause,
causing a different when you run
or the way the, the files been
located or when run.
Or
your application only fit in,
is have to work on different kinds like
you can put
on like,
um, it will have the minimal hardware
requirements, but for others it
is available to
apply on.
So we have understanding the software
engineering,
what the roles, what they,
they need to do.
Um,
now we gonna go to like the cost when
the software engineering developing or,
uh, working on a software
and how they manage
and w- the,
the effort and the cost,
um,
effect
based on the stage
when you develop or manage the
application.
So here we will have the formula, the
development work and the manage evolut--
based on the evolution
equal to the software production.
So this mean like you have a stage before
print out to the end user using for
production,
plus the time when you have to manage
based on the
error or based on the,
the change or the featuring have been,
will create the software production
while when
concurrently end user still using it
and you
concurrently updating it.
So the quicker development is not
always preferable because
the cost will be effect later on
if you not be careful and really s- take
care of your development.
The higher upfront cost may defray the
downstream
cost and poorly designed implemented
software is
critical cost factor.
So from here you can see from
the diagram we have the measure
of different stage, what is cost, and
once you go over the stage. So for
the co--
average cost of the software bugs are
the one that you have to manage.
So with the cost as the requirements
is minimal because you don't
have to do,
haven't been developing anything yet.
The cost will be minimal if you
take time and fix the requirements
carefully
and the cost design architecture gain more
based
on the way to design.
And next on is the code
or the developing stage,
and then unit testing based on the singles
features.
A little bit more time and cost
when figure out the bugs and the issues
And when you're going testing,
it's more cost when you're testing the
whole
system, system.
And even with the deployment
and maintenance, it's
after you product--
your software on production and been
used for many, many people.
All that can cost more once the bugs
coming
up because it's not only about the cost
that you
have been--
you have to spend for software engineering
to f-fix.
It's also the cost that you have to
lo-- you have lost when your
end user
not happy about your soft-- your,
your production.
We will go more about the software co--
we'll go more
about the breakdown maintenance cost.
So we will have three main things. One
is the corrective,
adaptive, and perfective. So
reactive change
for the corrective,
the reactive change after delivery
to,
the reactive change after delivery to
correct the
discovered problem, fault.
Uh, adaptive change that keep the software
usable as the environment
change,
OS and hardware platform. Perfective
is change driven
by user request, new or extension, pre--
better performance, and easier to use.
So these three stage is a different tree
of, uh, perfection or the maintenance cost
based on finished of-- the finishing
of your products.
So for these three stage, you
can break down the cost.
Where it's effective
ones is the
mainte--
the cost from the maintenance software
vendor, the
cost from the material spare part cost,
equipment and tools expense.
Those can be covered by, like, can
cover, understand that, like, a cost
when you're running a server,
when you have to
pay for the network, et cetera.
The labor cost is
you have to pay for your software
engineering.
And overhead cost is the other
can be count on. So not about the
cost and maintenance in the product.
It's also more about the
economics and management aspect
when you're managing your
resources,
which will help your production
less cost and control your cost based on
many-- the
projects and as the
project manager or the
software of the whole company.
So there's four thing you have to take
care of based
on the management. First
is human resources.
So what the project need, the team size,
and the role they
need to enroll, the skill level required,
and the effort
esti-estimation for the whole projects.
Next is time,
the schedule, and deadline.
How long it takes to finish one
feature? What's the milestone
and the stage you need to going
through based on time and the,
the constraint
of the,
uh, time limitation? Technical resources.
You need to decide what tool you need to
use.
The la--
For example, the languages, framework,
others that fit in the project and
which will
bring out the best or the optimize--
optimal,
uh, option for that kind.
Hardware requirements.
What you need for that?
You-- How many devi--
how many server you need?
How many
and how strong you need based on scale,
so you're not wasting the
extra pa-- performance
that the hardware come from.
Need those license that will fit in your
projects or not.
Next is the risk factor.
For three above is more about humans, uh,
order for, to running the projects,
but you need to
care about the change and the factor
that can be caused
the risk
when you're running
or managing the projects
as a software engineering
or you work at a software engineering.
So the scope of change
and technical challenge, you need to
worry about those.
And those will affect the
cost and technical resource,
and based on that, they will affect more
with the skill level, how they can easily
working through the, the risk
and cover up the,
cover up the,
the failure if ha-- is that happening.
And so,
the finally is why the software
engineering
is different than the other.
So the ever-present difficulty
is about the,
the different--
is about the complexity of the software,
human-intensive processes,
and the software malleable ability.
So
the compl-- we have four thing why
can claim
as the different in software engineering
and other.
First is the complexity.
So there's no two part
are alike, and so the software
is complex for its
size.
As your size of the software products
getting
scale up or getting bigger,
the complexity of your
product is much more
higher than the small scale.
The conformity is
much conformed to many human institution
and system
It's the
work team as many other people
with different kinds of role
to make the software
work and usable with the
optimal performance
can fit in the system that have been
run
at the beginning.
And changeability is a cons-
constant pressure for
change.
Why is a pressure of change?
Because of user can be changed,
what they like is differently,
and the technology development is
getting better and better every single
day.
You need to apply those
and apply what
end user need
or delete what they don't use anymore
to
upgrade your software smoother with the
great
performance. So the change
is not about you need a new
feature. It's a change because
you need your software getting better,
smooth,
and used, and easier for end user.
Invisibility,
software has no nature physical form
to picture.
As you can visualize,
there's software that r--
most of software right now go under the,
go underneath and visual for end
user. They don't understand what,
why they cannot view
the data flow. They cannot see that.
For those, it's invisible,
and they cannot understand why we
have the problems or not.
It's--
So that's why it's not easy to fix
when it's running,
and
it's, uh, physically you cannot see
until you have a GUI
to manage the--
to see the software running or the
simulation.
Estimating the software development
resource.
There's three main thing in
estimate
is the expert judgment estimate drawn from
the
experience of skilled people,
analogy-based estimate
by comparison with the similar past
project,
alchor-
algorithm,
algorithmic cost modeling, formula-based
model that estimate effort, and cost,
and schedule.
So with three is different kinds, like you
can need to...
It's three is different kind in
development.
The resource is based on the expert
who've been
familiar with the developing,
and the analogy
is you need to compare with the past
project how long your team
need to go for the past project
and the different of the, uh,
technical requirement skill
is will use,
so you can estimate the time and cost.
Algor-
algorithm
is required to make your
software getting smoother,
faster in millisecond
or--
and how those,
those, uh, fast, how, how your
performance will
affect the cost and schedule.
The challenging is the predicting
time, effort, and budget and how manage
cost compared to development cost.
So finally is some of the software
development concept
that you need to know, uh,
when you are the software or you're in the
team to developing a software production.
First,
need the identification, planning,
and designing,
implement the cost,
testing your what you wrote,
development the, uh,
development functionality testing with
the system attachment,
user experience testing
to see what they think about your
software, performance
load testing, how to see
your
what--
how heavy your software can handling in
the real world
or in the,
uh, testing environment. Compatibility of
testing
to that,
so you can easily testing in different
kind
system and devices. Security testing,
make sure your,
uh, software is safe
for end user.
Agile or you can have some other is
agile development, waterfall dev-
development, spiral
development,
offshore development, and maintenance.
Those all of the concept
that you can searching
more to know more about the workflow
and the technical,
what you need to know when you start
your project or in join to the team.
Finally is the reference
that I have searched for to
use. Thank you very much for hearing.